我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
and I am the fastest man alive.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world, I'm an ordinary forensic scientist,
但在尖端科研实验室的朋友们的帮助下
but secretly, with the help of my friends at S.T.A.R. Labs,
我秘密地打击犯罪  寻找跟我一样的超能力者
I fight crime and find other meta-humans like me.
我让杀害母亲的凶手自食其果
I hunted down the man who killed my mother,
但我们的世界也因此出现了新的威胁
but in doing so, I opened up our world to new threats,
我是唯一来得及阻止他们的人
and I am the only one fast enough to stop them.
我是闪电侠
I am The Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
极速要你死
Zoom wants you dead.
你真的觉得他做什么都很快吗
Do you think he can do everything really fast?
-你怎么样  狄格尔  -你太快了
- How you doing, Dig? - You're fast.
欢迎来到地球二
Welcome to Earth-2.
爸爸
Dad!
不要  不要
No! No!
凯特琳  那是你的名字  不是吗
Caitlin. That is your name, isn't it?
我讨厌凯特琳这个名字  我是冰霜杀手
I hate the name Caitlin. I'm Killer Frost.
罗尼和凯特琳的二重身都是坏蛋吗
Ronnie and Caitlin's doppelgangers are evil?
如果你要跟我们走  现在就得离开
If you're coming with us, we have to go.
西斯科
Cisco!
准备永远好关闭缺口吧
Get ready to close the breach for good,
极速要来了
Zoom's coming.
不
No!
他没死  他没死
He's not dead. He's not dead.
凯特琳
Caitlin
他没死  他没有
He's not dead. He's not.
-凯特琳  -怎么会这样
- Caitlin. - This isn't happening.
怎么又是这样
This isn't happening again.
有我在
Hey, I got you.
走吧
Come on.
-打开  -艾伦...
- Open it up. - Allen...
-我得回去  -不能打开
- I need to go back. - I can't do that.
-打开  -艾伦
- Open it up! - Allen!
缺口关闭了
The breaches are closed.
所有缺口都关闭了
All the breaches are closed.
就不能打开其中一个缺口吗
Why can't we just open one of 'em?
用来封闭缺口的夸克物质能量
The Quark Matter energy that we used to seal the breaches,
使得缺口永远也无法被打开了
it prevents them from being opened, ever again.
再也回不去我们的地球了
There's no going back to our world.
等等
Wait.
我们永远被困在这里了吗
We're trapped here for good?
对
Yes.
不  我们不能就这样放过极速
No, we can't just let Zoom get away with this.
他刚当着我们的面杀了杰伊
He just murdered Jay right in front of us.
我们一定能做点什么
There's got to be something we can do.
没办法了
There's not.
这次不能了
Not this time.
结束了
It's over.
不
No.
她怎么样了
How's she doing?
不好  我们想让她回家
Not good. We tried to get her to go home,
可她不愿走  所以你知道的
but she refused to leave, so, you know,
我只有陪着她等她睡着
I just sat with her until she fell asleep.
先是罗尼  现在又是杰伊
First Ronnie, now Jay.
对啊
Yeah.
我担心双重打击会给她造成怎样的伤害
I'm afraid what this double dose of grief is gonna do to her.
她已经饱受重创了
I mean, she's pretty shell-shocked.
她会没事的
She'll be fine.
斯诺很坚强  她会挺过去的
Snow's strong. She'll get past this.
但在这期间  我不会跟她讲
But in the meantime, I would not say anything to her
我地球上的她二重身的事
about her counterpart from my Earth.
也不会跟乔和爱瑞丝讲
That goes for Joe and Iris too.
为什么
Why?
因为他们的现实生活
Because you don't want to influence their reality
不该受到不正确的方式的影响
in ways that should not be influenced.
就像巴里穿越时空的这种方式吗
Like in the same way as when Barry time-travels?
没错  再说了
Exactly, but also,
说了又有什么意义呢
what's the point?
那些人与你们无关
Those people are not your people.
他们的生活也不是你们的生活
Their lives are not your lives.
过去不是  将来也绝不会是
Never were, never will be.
埋在心底  向前看
Bury it. Move on.
好吗
Yes?
好  我能做到
Yeah. That I can do.
艾伦
Allen?
这就是我们所做的
So that's what we did.
我们不谈地球二上的事
We didn't talk about Earth-2.
我们将那里所发生的事保密
We kept what happened there between the three of us
并且继续我们的生活
and got on with our lives
同时心里清楚我们如今无法阻止极速
knowing there was nothing we could do now to stop Zoom.
现实是  我们试图努力适应新环境
Instead, we tried to just adjust to our new circumstances
并且直面我们的损失
and cope with our losses.
杰伊的死亡是巨大损失
Jay's death took its toll...
给所有人留下伤痛  有人的伤更痛
left scars on all of us, some more than others.
我也试着不去想
And so to try and keep my mind
我感受过但不属于我的
off thoughts of the surreal other life
不现实的生活
I experienced that wasn't my own,
我不停地奔跑
I kept running,
等待着别的超能力者出来威胁大家
waiting for some other meta-human threat to rear its ugly head
好分散我的失落感
and distract me from the frustration I was feeling,
而一切早已注定
and as fate would have it,
水族馆
没让我等太久
I did not have to wait long.
一切正常
All good.
丑八怪  开饭了
Hey, ugly! It's time for dinner.
我猜布鲁斯已经死了
I think Bruce has gone belly up.
关掉电网
Power down the grid.
得把他捞起来
We're gonna have to fish him out.
这就是沃勒搞秘密项目的地方
So this is where Waller kept all her secret projects, huh?
只是其中之一  我还在了解中
One of many sites, I'm learning.
我肯定天眼会的新任指挥官
I'm sure the new director of A.R.G.U.S. will clean up
会收拾好沃勒留下的烂摊子
the mess that Waller left behind.
说得轻巧  亲爱的
Easier said than done, honey.
我妻子下决心要做的事就一定能做到
My wife can do anything she puts her mind to.
三号水池七级警报
Code seven in aquaria three.
重复  三号水池七级警报
I repeat, code seven in aquaria three.
水族馆出现了异常情况
There is a breach in the aquarium!
你们怎么还有水族馆
You have an aquarium? Why?
什么鬼
What the hell?
逗我玩儿呢吗
Are you kidding me?
七  六  五
Seven, six, five,
四  三  二  一
four, three, two, one.
-成功了  -时间到
- Yes! - Time.
没人比我更快了
Ain't nobody faster than me.
这可不一定了
I don't know about that.
得看巴里
Earth to Barry.
该你了  兄弟
It's your turn, dude.
是啊  是时候让年轻人见识见识
Yeah, it's time to show this little punk
谁才是世界上最快的叠胶杯高手
who the fastest stack attacker alive is.
你们玩吧  我就算了
One of you guys go ahead. I'm gonna pass.
你连个小比赛都害怕吗
You're afraid of a little competition?
不  只是现在没心情比赛
No, just not in a gaming mood right now.
好吧  那我猜本人就是冠军了
Okay, well, I guess that makes me champ.
对吧
Right?
好了  我得去见朋友了
Anyway, I'm gonna go meet up with some friends.
好
All right.
-拜  -拜
- Bye. - Bye.
下次再玩
Maybe next time.
我以为你才是家里好胜的那位
And I thought you were the competitive one in the family.
可不是嘛  怎么了  巴仔
I know, right? What's up, Bar?
没事  只是...
Nothing. Just--
我也不知道  只是觉得沃利不太喜欢我
I don't know, I don't think Wally likes me too much.
我们得解决这个问题
Well, we need to fix that.
你一直忙着在平行现实之间穿梭
I mean, you been so busy running between alternate realities,
你们俩都没机会在一起待过
you two haven't had a chance to spend any time together.
你想要我们一起做什么
What you want us to do together?
互相了解
Get to know each other,
找找你们有什么共同点
find something that you guys have in common.
他现在是家里的一员了  巴仔
He's part of the family now, Bar.
你得给他一个机会
You're gonna have to give it a chance.
我知道
I know.
好了  我先去睡了  好吗
All right, well, look, I'm gonna head to bed, all right?
-晚安  -晚安
- Good night. - Good night.
他有心事
Something is up with him,
而且我觉得不只是杰伊的死
and I don't think it's just Jay's death.
他从地球二回来之后就一直怪怪的
He's been acting weird ever since he came back from Earth-2.
他和你说过那边发生了什么吗
Did he say anything to you about what happened over there?
什么也没说  你呢
No, not a thing. You?
对了  我在想
Hey, so... I been thinking.
你总在没日没夜地工作
You've been working around the clock.
或许你该休息一下  回家去
Maybe you want to get some rest, go home.
好好睡一晚
You know, a good night's sleep
不会有坏处
wouldn't be the worst thing in the world.
我很好
I'm fine.
我明白
Look, I get it.
发生这种事  让你很痛苦
You're having a hard time with what happened.
这么短的时间内  很难接受
It's a lot to take so soon after--
我说了我很好
I said I'm fine.
你听见了吗
Did you hear that?
没有  怎么了
No, what?
凯特琳刚刚对我发火了
Caitlin just bit my head off.
她最近拚命工作  没有任何情绪
She's been all business, no emotion lately.
她最近...冷冰冰的
She's been...cold.
冷冰冰
Cold?
不是吧  西斯科
Come on, Cisco.
这可能是她开始变坏的迹象
This could be the beginning of her becoming evil.
你不担心这个吗
You're not worried about that?
我不担心这个
I'm not worried about that.
凯特琳不会变成冰霜杀手的
Caitlin's not gonna become Killer Frost.
地球二的事  你没和她提过吧
You haven't mentioned anything about about Earth-2, have you?
没有  我知道该怎么保守秘密
No, 'cause I know how to keep a secret.
好吧  我是说  她需要一些时间
All right, well, look, I mean, it's gonna take some time
才能缓过来
for her to heal.
我们必须支持她  让她保持忙碌
We just got to be there for her, keep her busy.
那不成问题
That shouldn't be a problem.
狄格  莱拉  你们好啊
Oh. Hey, Dig, Lyla.
你们怎么来了
What are you guys doing here?
我们是来提醒一下你的  巴里
We came to give you the head's up, Barry.
提醒什么
About what?
有个超能力者逃出了天眼会的羁押
A meta-human who escaped from A.R.G.U.S. Custody,
名字叫鲨鱼王
goes by the name King Shark.
鲨鱼王
King Shark?
就是几个月前想杀你的人形鲨鱼
You mean the half-man/half-shark that tried to kill you months ago.
我以为他死了
I thought he was dead.
那是天眼会想让你们相信的
That's what A.R.G.U.S. wanted you to believe
其实是被他们关起来了
when they snatched him up,
相信我  这个人形鲨鱼还活得好好的
but believe me, this half-shark is very much alive,
而他的生理本能驱动着他做一件事
and his biological imperative is telling him to do one thing.
就是杀死你  巴里
That's kill you, Barry.
我们需要大个点的闪电侠了
We're gonna need a bigger Flash.
你们是怎么知道鲨鱼王的事的
So how do you know about King Shark?
作为天眼会的新任会长
Well, as the new director of A.R.G.U.S.,
莱拉的任务就是给阿曼达·沃勒收拾烂摊子
Lyla's job is to clean up Amanda Waller's messes.
鲨鱼王是其中比较庞大和怪异的一个
King Shark was one of the bigger and weirder ones.
在她的指示下
And it appears under her directives,
过去的两年里  天眼会都在监控
A.R.G.U.S. had been monitoring meta-human activity
超能力者的活动
for the past two years.
为什么
Why?
想看看那些力量能否为之所用
Well, to see if any of those powers could be exploited.
变成武器
Weaponized.
你们怎么知道他要冲我来
How do you know that he's coming after me?
他被我们关着时  一直在说同一句话
While in our custody, he kept saying the same thing.
"极速想要闪电侠死"
"Zoom wants the Flash dead"
虽然他把我们安的追踪器拿掉了
And although he removed the tracker we had in him,
但在那之前我们收到的数据显示
the readings we did receive show that he was
他正朝着中城来了
headed towards Central City.
让他来吧
Let him come.
巴里  这家伙是个杀人机器
Barry, this thing is a killing machine.
我们是过来提醒你小心的  伙计
We just came here to warn you, man.
让天眼会来处理吧
Let A.R.G.U.S. handle it.
不  我不能  狄格
Nah, I can't do that, Dig.
很抱歉  但我们一整年都在被极速
I'm sorry, but all year, we've been sitting ducks
和他在地球二的追随者们追杀
for Zoom and his Earth-2 henchmen.
这是最后一次了
This is the last one.
我不会就这么等着他出击的
I'm not gonna just wait for him to attack.
我要主动出击  这是为了杰伊
I'm going after him first. I owe that to Jay.
威尔斯  他是你们地球上的
Wells, he's from your earth.
你对他有什么了解
What do you know about him?
本名叫沙伊·兰姆登  曾经是...
Real name, Shay Lamden, he was a--
听好了  他曾是海洋生物学家
get this--marine biologist
后来被我的粒子加速器变成了鲨鱼王
before my particle accelerator changed him into King Shark,
然后又被极速控制了
and Zoom put him under his control.
那他攻击巴里时  你们是怎么追踪他的
So how did you track him when he attacked Barry?
极速派他到这个地球来追杀巴里
Zoom sent him to this earth to kill Barry.
我就跟过来了
I just followed.
对  但你成功追踪了古鲁德
Yeah, but you did track Grodd down.
是不是也能找到鲨鱼王
Can you find King Shark too?
我可以试试
I can try.
好的
All right.
这些地点都在水域附近
Okay, well, all these locations are next to a body of water.
最多再过几个小时
There must only be a few hours
他肯定就要回到水里
before he needs to get back into the water
重新氧化血液
to re-oxygenate his blood.
我可以守在滨水区
I can take the Waterfront.
你能让你的人负责其余地方吗
Can you have your team handle the rest?
-我会吩咐他们的  -好的
- I'll get them on it. - All right.
兰姆登博士的二重身呢
What about Dr. Lamden's doppelganger?
或许他可以帮帮忙
Maybe he could help us somehow.
或许不行
Or not.
他似乎死于粒子加速器爆炸
Looks like he died when the particle accelerator exploded.
找找有没有近亲
What about next of kin?
他有个遗孀  塔尼娅·兰姆登博士
He's got a widow, Doctor Tanya Lamden.
她是鹦鹉螺实验室的研究科学家
She's a research scientist at Nautilus Labs,
研究领域是...等等...鲨鱼
And she studies-- wait for it--sharks.
或许你们俩可以去看看
Maybe the two of you can go and see
她有没有什么发现  可以帮助我们的
if she's discovered anything in her research that could help us.
-好的  -没问题
- Okay. - Sure.
好极了
Great.
-狄格  -怎么了
- Hey, Digg. - Yeah?
那个头盔你用得感觉如何
How's that helmet treating you?
最好能改进一下
Could use some improvements.
交给我吧
I'll get to work on it.
乔  有事吗
Hey, Joe, what's up?
巴仔  我和沃利谈了谈
Hey, Bar, I talked to Wally,
他想和你见一面
He wants to meet up with you.
好的
All right.
他今晚来家里做一个工程设计项目
He's working on his engineering project at our place tonight.
希望你能用你过人的智慧帮帮他
He would love some help from that big brain of yours.
乔  我很抱歉
Okay, Joe, look, I'm sorry,
我现在有些忙不过来了
Right now is kind of a crazy time.
什么  怎么了
What? What's going on?
还记得那个超能力鲨鱼吗
Remember that meta-human shark
帕蒂对付过他  他还攻击过我
that Patty was after and attacked me?
他回来了吗
He's back?
我还以为威尔斯...你知道的
I thought Wells--you know.
我也这么以为
Yeah, me too,
但他其实是被天眼会关起来了
but apparently, A.R.G.U.S. had him
然后又逃跑了  现在正朝中城来
and he escaped, and now he's heading for Central City.
我知道了
I get it.
我和沃利说改天吧
I'll tell Wally some other time.
不如这样吧
Hey, you know what?
没问题的  我会想办法
It's all good, I'll make it work.
告诉他今晚应该没问题
Tell him tonight should be fine.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
-是的  -谢了  巴仔
- Yeah. - Thanks, Bar.
没事  再见
Yeah, bye.
为什么
Why?
鹦鹉螺实验室
你们的粒子加速器爆炸都过去两年了
It's been two years since your particle accelerator exploded.
现在来问我丈夫的事  似乎有点晚了
Seems a little late to be asking questions about my husband,
不是吗
doesn't it?
你丈夫因为癌症去世的  是吗
Your husband passed away from cancer, correct?
我想你可以这么说
I suppose you could say that.
短短三天  他身体里的所有细胞
It only took three days for every cell in his body
就增长到失控了
to grow uncontrollably.
不管那是什么癌症  它把他变成了
Whatever cancer he had, it turned him into something...
非人类
not human.
其实我们就是为此而来
Well, that's why we're here, actually.
中城有一个超能力者
There's a meta-human in Central City
他的身体似乎变成了
whose body seems to be mutating
和你已故的丈夫一样的状况
in the same way as your late husband,
但是他没死  他成了危险的怪物
but he didn't die, he became a dangerous monster.
我的丈夫不是怪物
My husband was no monster.
她不是那个意思
That's not what she was implying.
这事和我有什么关系
What does this have to do with me?
我们读过你在这里做的关于鲨鱼的研究
We've read about the research you're doing here on sharks.
我有了些可喜的进展
Yeah, I've had some encouraging results,
虽说还是很初步
although still preliminary.
我们需要看看
We need to see it.
你说什么
I beg your pardon?
你的研究  所有的
Your research, all of it.
我同事的意思是
What my colleague means to say is that
如果你能让我们看看你的发现
if you could please let us take a look at your findings,
或许有助于我们阻止超能力者害人
it could help us stop this meta-human from hurting anyone.
你们是尖端科研实验室的  我能相信你们吗
You're with S.T.A.R. Labs. I'm just supposed to trust you?
求你了  兰姆登太太
Please, Mrs. Lamden.
这或许能帮助拯救生命
This could help save lives.
我会把我的发现发邮件给你
I'll email you what I have.
谢谢你
Thank you.
-太尖锐了点  -我是有话直说
- Little harsh. - I was being direct.
这么解释倒也可以
Yeah, well, that's one way to describe it.
自打你从地球二回来之后
You've been acting differently toward me
对我的态度就变了
ever since you got back from Earth-2.
你是怎么了  西斯科
What's your problem, Cisco?
没什么
Nothing.
咱们走吧
Let's just go.
区域一  没发现
Grid one, negative.
区域四  没发现
Grid four, negative.
汇报状态  区域二
Status check, grid two.
区域二  没发现
Grid two, negative.
有什么吗
Anything?
没有  伙计  什么都没有
No, man, nothing yet.
是啊  目前我们这里也没发现
Yeah, so far, nothing on our end either.
希望威尔斯的进展比我们这里好
Let's just hope Wells is doing better than we are.
费利西蒂怎么样了
Hey, how's Felicity doing?
我实话实说  巴里
Well, I'm not gonna lie, Barry,
刚开始挺艰难的  但是...
it was pretty rough there at first, but
你知道费利西蒂  她很坚强
you know Felicity, she's tough.
是啊  她都不回我的电话
Yeah, she's just not returning any of my calls.
她现在事很多
She has a lot going on right now.
老弟  我会让她在这些事结束后
Buddy, I'll ask if she can give you a call
给你打个电话的
when this is all over.
真想快点抓住这家伙
Just want to catch this thing, man,
把所有关于极速和地球二的事忘掉
have everything to do with Zoom and Earth-2 put behind us,
然后继续过我们的生活
so we can just move on with our lives.
你开始像奥利弗那样了  巴里
Starting to do that thing Oliver does, Barry,
将世界的重担扛在自己肩膀上
carry the weight of the world on your shoulders.
别这样了  这会拖慢你的速度
Got to stop that, man, it's gonna slow you down.
还是没有
Still nothing.
汇报状态  区域六
Status check, grid six.
等等  我们这里好像有情况
Hold on, I think we got something.
别说给沃勒收拾烂摊子了
So much for cleaning up after Waller's messes.
我们要是不赶快找到鲨鱼王
We don't find King Shark soon,
就要有人收拾我的了
someone's gonna be cleaning up after mine.
我们会找到他的  莱拉
We'll find him, Lyla.
好吧  我搜索了整个区域
All right, I searched the whole area.
他跑了
He's gone.
肯定跑不远
Couldn't have gotten far.
但是  他知道我们来了
Still, he knows we're here now.
我们失去了突袭的机会
We lost the element of surprise.
如果威尔斯能找到办法追踪他就不会
Not if Wells can figure out a way to track him.
与此同时  我们继续找
In the meantime, we'll keep looking.
好吧  我晚点和你们碰面
All right, I'll meet up with you guys later.
我得去见乔的儿子
I got to go see Joe's son.
好吧  我还以为只有我们那里关系乱
Okay, I thought our relationship was hard to follow.
再见
See ya.
他很快  约翰  别诧异了
He's fast, John, get over it.
没办法
Never.
乔说我应该让你看一看
Joe thought I should have you take a look.
这是我目前写的项目论文
So, this is what I got so far for my project essay
用于申请进入中城大学工程计划
to get into CCU's engineering program.
涡轮驱动汽车
涡轮机原型
涡轮超级跑车
Turbine supercars?
涡轮  就是喷气式发动机吗
Turbines? Like jet engines?
是啊  这种车用的引擎就像
Yeah, yeah, it'd use an engine like the ones they have
某些直升机用的一样  但是烧生物柴油
in some helicopters, only it'd run on biodiesel.
-酷  -真是酷
- Cool. - It's very cool.
你可能要解决一下
Yeah, you're gonna want to address
燃料消耗问题
the fuel economy issue here.
这是喷气机  肯定会消耗很多燃料
It is a jet, so it's gonna burn through a lot of fuel.
是啊  所以我想用生物柴油
Yeah, that's why I want to use biodiesel.
只要是能在有氧环境下燃烧的都可用
It'll run off of anything that burns with oxygen.
好  但你还有一个噪声的问题
No, okay, but you also got a sound issue.
会吵醒邻居
Gonna wake the neighbors...
绝对的
for sure.
还有其他的吗
Anything else?
我只是  想帮忙  你知道的
Well, I just... want to help, you know.
我只是想确保
I'm just trying to make sure
他们没有任何理由拒绝你
they don't have any reason to say no.
好吧
Okay.
抱歉  沃利  我不是有意...
Sorry, Wally, I didn't mean that--
这看起来真的很棒
It looks really good.
好吧  我们从头开始好了
All right, let's start over, okay?
这个...
Is it--
不如我们一起通读一下  找找解决办法
Why don't we go through it all together, work it out?
听起来不错
Sounds good.
太好了
Cool.
这简直是浪费时间
This is a complete waste of time.
我们在兰姆登博士的研究中肯定找不到
We're not gonna find anything in Doctor Lamden's research
怎么找出鲨鱼王的办法
to tell us how to find King Shark.
也许我可以看一看
Maybe I should take a look.
是啊  因为你是生物化学领域的博士
Oh, yeah, 'cause you're the doctor with a specialty in bio-chem.
我只是说  你也许会需要
I'm just saying maybe you could use
另一双眼睛的帮助  考虑到...
another set of eyes, considering.
考虑到什么
Considering what?
考虑到你近来的表现
Considering the way you've been acting lately.
你这是什么意思
What does that mean?
你不像你自己了  凯特琳
You are not yourself, Caitlin,
这吓坏我了
And it's freaking me out,
因为你眼里有一种冷酷
'cause you have this icy look in your eye
就像在那边一样
just like you did over there.
在那边
Over there?
你是说地球二
You mean Earth-2?
不是  不
No. Uh, no.
我想说的是...
Um, what I meant to say was--
你见到了我的二重身  对不对
You met my doppelganger, didn't you?
什么  没有
What? No.
西斯科
Cisco.
我不应该说的
Look, I'm not supposed to say anything.
为什么
Why not?
因为我不应该说
Because I'm not supposed to say anything.
弗朗西斯科·拉蒙  如果你不开始交代
Francisco Ramon, if you don't start talking--
好吧  没错  我见过你的二重身
Okay, fine, yes, I met your doppelganger.
她叫冰霜杀手  是冷酷无情的冰雪女魔
She's a coldhearted Ice Queen named Killer Frost,
非常喜欢杀人的超能力者
a meta-human who enjoyed killing a lot.
好了  说出来了
There, great.
这下哈里得杀了我  把我扔出去了
Now Harry's gonna kill me and throw myself across the room.
西斯科  我不是超能力者
Cisco, I'm not a meta-human.
我知道  但是你的表现
Okay, I hear you, but you're acting
就和她在那边的表现一样
just like she did over there.
你变得不爱说话  冷漠
You're being shut off. You're being detached.
变得冷淡
You're being cold.
因为我现在必须这样
Because I have to be right now.
我刚看着杰伊在我面前被杀死
I just watched Jay get killed right in front of my eyes,
才开始感到一切又正常了
just when I was starting to feel normal again,
我才开始决定去爱了
just when I was beginning to love.
如果我让自己去感受
So if I let myself feel,
让自己释放所有的伤痛与愤怒
if I let all of that pain and anger out,
那就永远不会停止
it's never gonna stop,
而且那对我也没有帮助
and that's not gonna help me either,
所以我们还是继续研究
so let's just get back to this research
想办法找出鲨鱼王吧
and figure out how to find King Shark.
好吧
Okay.
找到你了
Here you are.
就像在家里  总是在工作
Yup, just like back home, always working.
我想找到鲨鱼王的下落
I'm trying to locate this King Shark.
他来在地球一了吗
He's here? On this Earth?
是的  其实是极速
Yes, it turns out our friend Zoom
让他来这里杀闪电侠的
brought him here to kill the Flash.
貌似他和我们一样困在这里了
Looks like he's stuck here just like we are.
好像是的  所以我要在他伤害更多人前
It looks like he is, and so I need to figure this out
把这个弄明白  杰西
before more people get hurt, Jessie, so...
概率分布算法吗
Probability distribution algorithm?
部分匹配策略  没错
Partial matching strategies, yes.
根据什么
Based on what?
语义轨迹  水  中城  闪电侠
Semantic trajectories -- water, Central City, the Flash.
那移动特性呢
What about mobility behaviors?
杰西
Jessie.
你想我离开那个房间
Look, you wanted me out of that room,
但是现在你却不想我在这里
but now that I am, you don't want me here.
让我帮忙吧
Just let me help, please.
去拿支马克笔
Grab a marker.
好
Yeah.
最难之处是放大扭矩  不增大阻力
Hardest part was amping the torque without increasing drag.
重一点的发动机只会让速度减慢
A heavier engine would only slow things down,
但这个改进的版本应该能
but this streamlined version should optimize
同时提高扭矩和功率
both the torque and the horsepower.
我只是担心  这样还是不够
Yeah, I'm just worried it's -- won't be enough still.
这样吧
Here, let's do this--
利用一对一传输的传动齿轮箱
use a one-to-one transfer gearbox
转移发动机的输出轴
to drop the output shaft of the engine,
反向旋转  把更多的能量送至变矩器
reverse rotation and send more power to the torque converter.
我来找你不是让你替我做完
I didn't come here for you to just do it for me.
我们不是要一起解决吗
I thought we were gonna work on this together.
我们是啊  我
Yeah, we are, I'm--
我只是想加快进度
I'm just trying to speed up the process.
为什么
Why?
你有更重要的地方要去吗
What, you got somewhere better to be?
没有  沃利  我  沃利
No, Wally, I'm-- Wally.
好吧
All right.
你对我有意见吗
Do you have a problem with me?
谁会对你有意见啊
Who could have a problem with you?
你不是巴里吗  完美无瑕
You're Barry, right? You're perfect.
从来不会做错事
Never do anything wrong.
哪里都有你
Always this, always that.
沃利
Wally.
看看你的周围
I mean, take a look around you, man.
这屋里的每张照片都有你的身影
You're in every picture in this room.
谢谢你的帮忙
You know, thanks for your help,
但这个我自己来搞定
but I'll just take care of this myself.
闪电侠呢
Where's the Flash?
我知道闪电侠在这
I know the Flash is here.
我能闻到他的味道
I can smell him.
大家赶快出去
Everybody get out!
快走  快走
Come on. All right, come on.
他在哪里
Where is he?
我在这里
Right here!
闪电侠  极速要你死
Flash, Zoom wants you dead!
我知道
Yeah, I know.
然后你就能回家了是吧
Then you get to go home, right?
知道吗
Well, guess what, man.
极速送你来这的缺口
The breaches that Zoom used to bring you here,
都没了  是我关闭的  永久地关闭了
they're all gone. I closed 'em, for good!
再也没有极速
There's no more Zoom.
再也回不到你的地球了
There's no way back to your Earth.
你要被关在这里很长时间
You're gonna be locked up here for a very long time.
你也许很快  但是不如我在水中快
You might be fast, but not as fast as I am in water!
你抓不到我的  闪电侠
You're not gonna catch me, Flash!
好
Okay.
你没事吧
You okay?
没事
Oh, yeah, I'm good.
他弄坏了点东西  但我没事
Think he broke a few things, but I'm good.
我的房主保险应该不包括
I don't suppose my homeowner's insurance
鲨鱼风暴的袭击
covers a "Sharknado" attack.
真不明白你们这些人
I don't understand you people.
大鲨鱼像急救人一样冲破你们的房子
Jaws busts through your house like the Kool-Aid Man,
“酷爱牌汽水吉祥物以及动画人物”
然后闪电侠出现  你们却一点不怕
the Flash shows up, and y'all just act like it's no big deal.
这两年  我们在中城
Yeah, well, we've had a lot of weird things happen
遇到了不少这样的怪事
in Central City over the past two years.
比一只会说话  穿着裤子的鲨鱼还奇怪
Weirder than a talking shark wearing pants?
你会更惊讶的
Man, you'd be surprised.
大家都没事吧
Hey, you guys. Everybody okay?
没事  我们没事
Yeah, yeah, we're fine.
你刚才躲在床底下吗
What'd you go hide under your bed?
沃利  别这样
Wally, come on.
乔和爱瑞丝跟我说过很多关于你的事
You know, Joe and Iris told me a lot about you,
说得你好像能在水上行走或还有别的能耐
made it out like you could walk water, or something,
但是从来没说过
but they never mentioned anything
你是个胆小鬼
about you being a coward.
够了
Okay, enough!
回头见
See you guys later.
老爸  你要和他好好谈谈
Dad, you need to talk to him.
不用  没事  我明白
No. It's fine, I get it.
我知道你们爱我
Look, I know you guys love me,
但请别再跟沃利说我有多好
but please stop telling Wally all this great stuff about me.
跟他说真话吧  我并不完美
Start telling him the truth. I'm not perfect.
我犯的错  有时连闪电侠也无法修补
I make mistakes that even the Flash can't fix.
好
Okay.
你在地球二上发生了什么事
What happened with you on Earth-2?
真相
The truth.
我不该告诉你们  但是
I shouldn't... tell you guys this, but...
我见过你们的二重身
I met your doppelgangers.
你是家里的警察  一名出色的警察
You were the cop in the family, a good one too.
我就说我会是出色的警察
I told you I would've made a good cop.
想都别想
Don't get any ideas.
那我呢
What about me then?
你是酒吧歌手
You were a lounge singer.
其实你有天籁般的嗓音
Yeah, you had this amazing voice, actually,
但你根本不喜欢我
but you didn't like me at all.
你怪我让爱瑞丝当上警察
You actually blamed me for Iris becoming a cop,
说她当警察的原因是
said that she only became one
去帮助她自私丈夫的事业
To help her selfish husband's career.
等下
Wait.
我们结婚了
We were married?
我们去看乔的演出
And we went to go see Joe perform.
就是那个时候出了事
And that's when everything went wrong.
几个极速手下的超能力者出现了
Um, some metas that worked for zoom showed up,
他们在找我
they were looking for me.
他们知道我不应该在那
They knew I wasn't supposed to be there,
然后他们发动了攻击
and they attacked,
你在交火中受了伤
and you got caught in the crossfire,
然后  死了
and...You died.
我知道那并不是你
I knew that it wasn't you,
任何那边的事情都无关这里的生活
that none of that was this life,
但是
but...
我是说  眼看着那一切发生  在那里生活
I mean, watching it happen in front of me, living that,
我并没有觉得不同  毕竟那也是真实的
it didn't feel any different, because it was all still real.
杰伊提醒过我穿越过去的时候
And Jay warned me not to get emotionally sucked in
不要被那边的情感吸引
when I went there,
但这还是发生了
and then that's exactly what happened.
现在地球二的乔·韦斯特因我的出现死了
And now Joe West on Earth-2 is dead, because I showed up.
巴里  那  那不是你的错
Barry, that-- that's not your fault.
就是我的错
Yeah, it is my fault.
全都是我的错
It's all my fault.
极速
Zoom,
这个鲨鱼王
this King Shark,
杰伊的死
Jay's death,
都是因为我
it's all because of me.
现在我又让整个世界
And then I just left an entire world
被极速控制了
at Zoom's mercy.
你刚觉得可以安全回到市郊了
Just when you thought it was safe to go back in the suburbs,
鲨鱼王就出现在了你家门口
King Shark shows up at your house.
我都不知道他是怎么找到我的
I mean, I don't even know how he found me.
我在家的时候又不是闪电侠
It's not like I was the Flash while I was at home.
一定有什么原因
Must be a reason.
对
Yeah.
你们想出找到鲨鱼王的办法了吗
Have you figured out a way to track King Shark yet?
没有  我没有足够的信息
No, I don't have enough information
来写一个准确的定位算法
to create an accurate location algorithm.
兰姆登博士的研究呢
What about Dr. Lamden's research?
能帮上我们吗
Anything that can help us?
起初我并不觉得
I didn't think so at first,
但是后来我发现了些可能有用的东西
but then I found something that I think might help us.
鲨鱼是食肉动物
Sharks are predators.
为了追踪猎物
In order to track their prey,
他们会用一种被动电场定位法
they use what's known as passive electrolocation.
被动电场定位
Passive electrolocation?
是的  他们可以识别鱼身体周围的
Yes, it's how they sense the bioelectric potential
生物电场
around a fish's body.
鲨鱼王识别了巴里体内的电能
King Shark senses electricity in Barry's system.
好  这解释了鲨鱼王是怎么找到巴里的
Okay, that explains how King Shark can track Barry,
但是这对我们找到他有什么帮助
but how is that going to help us track him?
以其人之道还其人之身
We flip it.
与其让鲨鱼王成为捕食者
Instead of King Shark being the predator,
我们让他变成猎物
we make him the prey,
用被动电场定位法追踪他
and track him using active electrolocation.
我们给卫星重新编程
We reprogram our satellite to generate
发射一个特定的电场
a specific electric field and then measure
来测量符合一只重达一吨的行走鲨鱼
any electrical distortions that correlate
的电场畸变
with a 1-ton walking shark.
这样就能帮我们找到他了
That'll help us get him.
你来帮我吗
You help me out?
好啊
Sure.
很好
Great.
找到他之后通知我们
Let us know when you locate him
然后我们来解决
and we'll take it from there.
好吧
Okay.
我们把队伍集合吧
Let's get the team ready.
那到底是什么
What exactly is that?
那个  我的朋友  是诱饵
That, my friend, is bait.
你造了一个闪电侠诱饵
You made a Flash lure?
这么短的时间内
It's the best I could come up
我能弄出的最好的就是它了
with given the time frame.
它可以模仿并加强
It's rigged to mimic and enhance
巴里体内产生的电场
the electric field Barry's body generates.
只要鲨鱼王嗅一下它
King Shark takes one whiff of that,
就可以放《大白鲨》主题曲了
cue the "Jaws" soundtrack.
“1975年斯皮尔伯格指导电影
影片结尾大白鲨被炸死”
我还在里面放了麻醉剂
Also stuffed it with enough tranqs
足够昏迷他一个月了
to knock him out for a month.
这样应该很容易把他钓上来了
Should make him a lot easier to reel in.
那个集装箱呢
And that container.
够不够结实能困住昏迷之后的他
Strong enough to hold him once he's sedated?
那是用叵金属做的  是无法穿透的
It's made of promethium metal. It's impenetrable.
同时  我们可以用这个和诱饵上的摄像头
Meanwhile, we'll be able to keep track of King Shark with this,
来追踪鲨鱼王
and the cameras that are on the lure.
无论他做什么  我们都看得到
Whatever he does, we'll have eyes on him.
那好吧  我们去钓鱼吧
All right, then. Let's go fishing.
凯特琳  我不明白为什么
Caitlin, I don't understand why
这种情况下不是我来充当昆特的角色
I can't be the one playing Quint in this scenario.
“电影《大白鲨》中的捕鱼能手”
应该是我在前线  不是你
I should be the one out there, not you.
我必须要做这件事
I need to do this.
你知道昆特最终死了的  对吧
You know Quint dies, right?
水是这只怪物的自然栖息地
Water is this monster's natural habitat.
他在这里要强壮得多
He's gonna be a lot stronger here.
你确定要这么做了吗
You sure about this?
今晚就来做个了结
This ends tonight.
也许他不会上这个当
Maybe he's not gonna fall for this
他是只鲨鱼  他会来的
He's a shark. He'll come.
有什么发现吗  西斯科
Anything, Cisco?
没有  没有什么像是他的东西出现
Uh, nope, nothing that looks like it could be him.
你给卫星编程了的  对吗
You programmed the satellite though, right?
是的  哈里
Yes, Harry.
我的意思是  你输入的参数正确吗
I mean, you punched in the correct parameters?
你在侮辱我的智商
You're insulting my intelligence.
但是他们已经等了几个小时了
But they've been waiting for hours.
我知道他们已经在那几个小时了
I know they've been out there for hours,
但是你这是在侮辱我的智商  懂了吗
but you're insulting my intelligence with this, okay?
-我知道了  -好吧
- I know. - Okay.
你设定的畸变范围是对的  是吧
Hey, you set the right distortion scope, right?
来真的  好吧
Oh, for real? Okay.
你知道吗  我们现在来玩个游戏
You know what, we're gonna play a game here.
游戏叫做  如果你是地球二来的
It's called, if you're from Earth-2,
就请给我闭嘴  好吗
you're gonna be quiet, okay?
好吧
Yeah.
巴里  你还好吗
Hey, Barry, are you okay?
自从极速在这里和地球二都打败我之后
Ever since Zoom beat me here and on Earth-2,
我就在一直逃避事情
I've been running away from things,
而不是直面它们
instead of towards them.
我不能再这样了
That needs to change.
我们会帮你的
We'll get you back there.
我知道
I know.
把这个当做你迈出的第一步
Think of this as your first step.
或者说游出的
Or swim.
伙计们  那是什么
Uh, hey, guys. What is that?
大法师来了  伙计们  敌人来袭
The big Kahuna. Guys, incoming.
他在向诱饵移动
He's headed for the bait!
他把诱饵吃下去了
He ate the lure!
把他钓上来  好吗
Reel him in, all right?
来吧
Come on.
他去哪了
Where'd he go?
他往码头那边去了
He's headed for the docks.
快走
Go, go, go.
准备开火
Get ready to fire!
那些枪是阻止不了我的  闪电侠
Those guns won't stop me, Flash.
我会先杀了你  然后再杀了他们
First I'll kill you, then I'll kill them.
是吗  那我们试试吧
Oh, yeah? Let's do this then!
来吧
Come on!
他在干什么
What is he doing?
他在给水通电
He's electrifying the water.
我们可以收线了
Now we can reel him in.
捕得漂亮  巴里
Hell of a catch, Barry.
是啊
Yeah.
我们最好确保不让他变成
Let's just make sure he doesn't become
"漏网之鱼"
"The one that got away."
不会再出这种事了
Won't let that happen again.
你打算怎么处置他
What are you gonna do with him?
还不知道  但有一点可以确定
I don't know yet. But one thing's for sure,
天眼会想把鲨鱼王变成武器的计划
A.R.G.U.S.'s plans to turn King Shark into a weapon
随着阿曼达·沃勒的死而破灭了
died with Amanda Waller.
我觉得我们最好花时间
I think our time would be better served
研究一下他的由来
learning about how he came to be
还有如何治好他
and how to cure him.
知道吗  你应该和兰姆登博士聊聊
You know, you should really talk to Dr. Lamden.
她做过很多研究
She's done a lot of research,
我觉得对你有帮助
and I think it could be helpful to you.
我会去的
I'll do that.
很高兴再次见面
Nice to see you again.
真是多谢了  狄格
Well, thanks a lot, Dig.
我应该谢谢你  巴里
Hey, I got to thank you, Barry.
让莱拉首开得胜
Got Lyla get her first win,
还让我看到你在水上跑
I got to watch you run on water.
简直是恩赐
It was biblical.
巴里  当我在阿富汗作战时
Look, Barry, when I was in Afghanistan,
我失去了很多朋友  兄弟
I lost a lot of friends-- brothers.
我知道失去杰伊是怎样的感受
So losing Jay, I know what it feels like.
质疑自己  为他的死自责
Question yourself. Blame yourself for his death.
这种负罪感  可以把你撕碎
And that guilt, it can tear you apart,
相信我  伙计
but trust me, man,
你必须去控制它
You got to get control of it,
否则它会扯碎你的内心
Or it'll rip you up inside.
利用这种感受  让它指引你
Use this, man, let it guide you,
这种事也就再也不会发生了
so it never happens again.
-好的  谢了  -别客气
- All right, thanks, man. - You got it.
替我给大家问个好吧
Say hi to everyone for me, all right?
我会的
I will.
好吧  这确实有点吓人了
Yeah, okay. That's kind of freaky.
对  看到了吧  我说过的
Yeah, yeah, see? I told you.
奥利弗  什么事
Hey, Oliver, what's up?
吉特斯咖啡厅
你读东西还真是慢
You're a really slow reader.
所以呢
So?
我想要一辆这种超级汽车
I want one of these super cars.
用途
我是说尤其...
I mean, especially
我能用它减掉陈年积累的脂肪
if I can run it off the bacon grease I collect? I mean--
天呐  沃利
Man, Wally.
我太佩服了
I'm so impressed.
谢谢
Thanks.
其实巴里给了我很多帮助
But Barry gave me a lot of help, so...
是的  没错  不过这都是你的主意
Yeah, he did, but this was all your idea,
这是你的勤奋努力  都是你
This is your hard work. It's all you.
巴里也会这样说的
Barry'd say the same thing.
会吗
Would he?
听着  沃利
Look, Wally.
巴里11岁时  我和爱瑞丝就收留了他
Iris and I took Barry in when he was 11,
他过来和我们生活
and the reason he came to live with us
是因为他的妈妈被杀害了
is because his mother was murdered,
他的爸爸因此蒙冤入狱
and his father was wrongfully imprisoned for it.
自从那天起  我一直对他关怀备至
And I have been overprotective of that kid since that day.
给他全部的爱与支持
We gave him all the love and support he needed
帮他渡过难关
to get through that tragedy
他才能有现在的样子
and become the man he is now.
所以那种自豪感
So that--that pride
我和爱瑞丝谈起他时的自豪感
you see when iris and I are talking about him,
是因为...
is because...
庆幸自己给了他巨大的改变
things could have gone very differently.
但他并不完美
But he's not perfect,
他也不比你和艾瑞丝  或任何人更重要
and he's not favored over you or Iris or anybody else.
你没什么可担心的
So you have nothing to worry about.
他是我儿子
He's my son...
就像你一样
just like you are.
你摆弄这些做什么呢
What are you doing with those?
我在调试波长触发器
I'm adjusting the wavelength trigger,
看看能不能让它们再次工作
See if I can get these to work over here.
那样你就能抓住穿越者了吗
So you can catch some breachers?
我的老天
dear god!
凯特琳  你的手好冰
Caitlin, your hands are freezing.
凯特琳  我一直不喜欢这个名字
Caitlin. I've always hated that name.
不要
Oh, no.
糟了  糟了  开始了  你开始变成...
No, no, no, it's starting. You're starting to become--
冰霜杀手吗
Killer Frost?
这不妥
That ain't right.
这不妥  这么做太过分了
That ain't right, that's just rude.
是谁让你这么玩的
Who put you up to this?
是巴里指使你的  对不对
Barry put you up to this, didn't he?
我早该明白你们两个很...
Oh, I should've know you two were--
-很冷酷  -没错
- Cold? - Yeah.
你活该的
You deserve it
竟然以为我会变成冰霜杀手
for thinking that I could ever become like her.
西斯科  你不用再担心我了
Cisco, you need to stop worrying about me.
我也许难过  我也许想一个人静静
I may be sad, I may want to be alone for a little while,
但我向你保证
but I promise you,
这个地球绝不会有冰霜杀手  好吗
Killer Frost will never exist on this earth, okay?
况且  你给我化验过
Besides, you tested me.
我都没有超能力者基因
I don't even have the meta-human gene,
请你不要再为我担心了  好吗
So please stop worrying about me, okay?
好
Okay.
走吧  巴里叫我们上去
Come on, Barry wants us upstairs.
不过说真的  你应该研究下血液循环
For real, though, you got to work on that circulation.
你可能患有雷诺式病
You might have Raynaud's or something.
你知道雷诺氏病吧
You know what Raynaud's is?
我是名医生  西斯科
I'm a doctor, Cisco.
了不起  了不起  大伙儿到齐了
Hail, hail, the gang's all here.
有什么事
What's good?
我要向所有人道歉
I need to apologize to you all.
去年我做了个选择
Last year I made a choice
穿越到过去救我妈妈
to go back in time and save my mother,
这个选择带来了很多后果
and that choice had a lot of consequences
这些后果会缠着我一生
that will haunt me for the rest of my life,
我知道它们也在缠着你们
just like I know it haunts all of you too.
极速
Zoom,
杰伊的死
Jay's death...
全都因我而起
it's all because of me,
但这些选择是我的
but I own those choices.
是我们打开了地球二的入口
We're the ones who opened the door to Earth-2.
是我们把极速引到这里
We're the ones who brought Zoom here,
但也会是我们去阻止他
but we are also the ones who are gonna stop him.
怎么做
How?
我们要怎么阻止极速  艾伦
How are we gonna stop Zoom, Allen?
我还不知道
I don't know yet.
但这些缺口没有永远关闭
But those breaches aren't closed forever,
我们和地球二的事也没有结束
and we're not done with Earth-2.
杰伊没有白白死去
Jay's death was not in vain.
我们会再次见到极速
We will meet Zoom again,
等到那时  我会打败他
and the next time, I will beat him,
无论他是何方神圣
whoever that monster is.
好吧  这下事情复杂了
Well, this is a complication.